Ehrmann, Henry W. (Heinrich); Papers ger013
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Correspondence, 1941-1988; 2; 244 file folders
  - General Correspondence, 1941-1988; 2.1; 131 file folders, including 95 individual correspondents and 24 institutions
    - Praeger, Frederick A. (Westview Press -- 1983), 1988 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 73)
    - Quermonne, Jean-Louis, 1981-1984 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 74)
    - Remond, René, 1988; Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 75)
    - Richter, Ernst, 1987 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 76)
    - Rieser, Leonard M. (Dartmouth College), 1965-1975 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 77)
    - Rogers, Lindsay (Columbia Univ), 1948; 1951 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 78)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1946; 1948 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 79)
    - Rosenstock-Huessy, Eugen, 1962; 1964 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 80)
    - Roucek, Joseph S. (Hofstra College), 1941-1942 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 81)
    - Safran, William (Univ. of Colorado, Boulder), 1952; 1982-1983 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 82)
    - Salwyn Schapiro, Jack, 1944-1967 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 83)
    - Schlesinger, Arthur jr. (Harvard University), 1949-1959 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 84)
    - Seligmann, Herbert J., 1941; 1969 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 85)
    - Sontheimer, Kurt (Geschwister-Scholl-Institut für Politische Wissenschaft, Univ. München, 1979-1988 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 86)
    - Stearns, Mr. and Mrs. Robert L., 1948-1968 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 87)
    - Tiedemann, K. (Universität Freiburg i. Br), 1982 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 88)
    - Touchard, J. (Fondation Nationale des Sciences Politiques), 1964; 1968 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 89)
    - Tunc, André (Université de Paris I), 1974; 1976 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 90)
    - Wahl, Nicholas (New York University), 1991 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 91)
    - Warburg, James P., 1949; 1951 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 92)
    - Wilson, Arthur (Dartmouth College), 1961 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 93)
    - Zink, Harold (Ohio State Univ), 1948; 1952 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 94)
    - Zuelzer, Wolf W. 1982, 1986 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 95)
    - Reaction to Ehrmann's Letter on Martin Luther King: miscellaneous correspondents, 1969 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous English Correspondents: no institution provenance indicated, 1942-1985; Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous French Correspondents: no institution provenance indicated, 1941-1986; Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous German Correspondents: no institution provenance indicated, 1952-1987; Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 4)
    - "Der Abend" (with reference to the John F. Kennedy Institute, the Free University of Berlin, 1972-1973 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 5)
    - Colorado State College of Education at Greeley, 1952; 1954 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 6)
    - Columbia University, NY, 1952-1968 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 7)
    - Cornell University, 1951-1952 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 8)
    - Dartmouth College, 1952-1982; Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 9)
    - Dept. of State, 1948 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 10)
    - Harvard University, 1952-1986; Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 11)
    - McGill University, 1975-1984 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 12)
    - The New School for Social Research, N.Y.C., 1941-1954 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 13)
    - Princeton University, 1951-1952; 1986 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 14)
    - Queens College, 1942; 1944 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 15)
    - La Sorbonne, Paris, 1973-1974 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 16)
    - Stanford University, 1949; 1980 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 17)
    - Supreme Court of the U.S., 1944; 1952 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 18)
    - Universität Mannheim, 1979-1983 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 19)
    - University of California, Irvine, 1978; 1980 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 20)
    - University of California, San Diego, 1979-1980; Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 21)
    - University of Colorado, 1948-1983; Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 22)
    - University of Hartford, 1977-1987 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 23)
    - University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, 1949; 1979 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 24)
    - University of Oregon, 1952; 1969 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 25)
    - University of Virginia, Charlottesville, 1948-1949 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 26)
    - U.S. Senate, 1944-1959 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 27)
      Including a copy of J. F. Kennedy's letter.
    - Yale University, 1950-1968; Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 28)
    - Correspondents affiliated with educational Institutions, 1942-1986 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 29)
    - Publishers, Editors, Periodicals, 1941-1984 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 30)
    - German Editors, 1972; 1981 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 31)
    - Miscellaneous Institutions (in English), 1941-1982 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 32)
    - Miscellaneous French Institutions, 1954-1987; Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 33)
    - Miscellaneous German Institutions, 1968-1986 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 34)
    - Festschrift correspondence, 1981-1984 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 35)
    - Book donations to Wesleyan University, 1993-1994 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 36)
  - Correspondence with the Former Prisoners-of-War or Pertaining to Their Reeducation Program, 1945-1950; 1978; 2.2; 113 file folders, including 109 individual correspondents
    The sub-series contains correspondence from and to the former German prisoners-of-war who met Ehrmann during the reeducation program organized by the War Department. The letters - in several cases written by the prisoners' family members as well - almost entirely date from the period immediately subsequent to the POWs' release and their return to Germany. Therefore, they are a valuable source of information about the living conditions in occupied Germany, the country's political transformation, and the correspondents' adaptation to new circumstances.
    - Alphabetical list of POW correspondents, Undated (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 1)
    - Andersch, Alfred, 1947-1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 2)
    - Auerbach, Walter, 1949 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 3)
    - Bader, Richard, 1947-1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 4)
    - Bauer, Franz J., 1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 5)
    - Bernard, Paul, 1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 6)
    - Beust, Joachim von, 1946-1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 7)
    - Blanke, G. H., 1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 8)
    - Boecker, Friedrich, 1946-1949 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 9)
    - Borst, Robert, 1947-1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 10)
    - Bressel, Willi, 1946 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 11)
    - Carstens, Heinrich, 1946-1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 12)
    - Eberhardt, Manfred, 1946 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 13)
    - Eckenbach, Willy, 1946-1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 14)
    - Elsholz, Rudolf, 1947-1949 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 15)
    - Eppinger, Anton, 1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 16)
    - Fackert, Willi, 1946-1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 17)
    - Fischbacher, Sebastian, 1946 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 18)
    - Flammger, Frank, 1946 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 19)
    - Friese, Franz, 1946-1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 20)
    - Gerlach, Joachim, 1946 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 21)
    - Gessman, Erich, 1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 22)
    - Goetze, Rolf, 1947-1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 23)
    - Gotze, Walter, 1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 24)
    - Greulich, E. R. [Rudolf], 1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 25)
    - Hähnel, Alfred, 1946-1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 26)
    - Härtel, Heinz, 1946-1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 27)
    - Hallstein, Walter, 1946-1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 28)
    - Hammer, George, 1947-1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 29)
    - Hausner, Karl-Heinz [Hertz, Walter], 1946-1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 30)
    - Heine, Genosse, 1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 31)
    - Hendus, Heinrich, 1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 32)
    - Henning, Adolf, 1946-1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 33)
    - Hepperle, Paul, 1946-1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 34)
    - Hess, Hans, 1946; 1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 35)
    - Heyne, Friedrich, 1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 36)
    - Hieronymi, Hans, 1946-1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 37)
    - Hilbert, Alois, 1946-1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 38)
    - Hooge, Alfred, 1978 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 39)
    - Hubauer, Alfons, 1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 40)
    - Huber, Berndt, 1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 41)
    - Hübscher, Hans, 1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 42)
    - Jahn, Werner, 1946-1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 43)
    - Jeffke, Werner, 06/30/1946 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 44)
    - Jungfermann, Hermann and Maria, 1946-1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 45)
    - Kall, Rolf, 1946-1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 46)
    - Kendelbacher, Kurt, 1946-1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 47)
    - Kenner, Heinz, 1946-1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 48)
    - Kirchbach, Erwin, 1947-1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 49)
    - Kloss, Walter, 1946 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 50)
    - Köhnlein, Walter, 1946-1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 51)
    - Kölz, Theodor, 1946-1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 52)
    - Kornrumpf, Martin, 1947; 1949 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 53)
    - Kunter, Gerda, Undated (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 54)
    - Kuntze, Karl, 1946-1949 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 55)
    - Kusterer, Ferdinand, 1947-1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 56)
    - Lampe, Friedrich, 1946 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 57)
    - Lapsien, Georg, 1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 58)
    - Lautenbach, Edwin, 1946 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 59)
    - Leetz, Arnold, 1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 60)
    - Mack, Wilhelm, 1946-1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 61)
    - Mänz, Hans-Heinrich, 08/02/1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 62)
    - Markmiller, Max, 1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 63)
    - Maurath, Johann, 1946-1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 64)
    - Meyer, Emil, 1946 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 65)
    - Meyer, Heinz, 1946-1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 66)
    - Meyer-Oelschigk, Rolf, 1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 67)
    - Meyn, Erich, 1947-1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 68)
    - Michael, Rudolf, 1946-1950 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 69)
    - Mixius, F. K., 1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 70)
    - Mörtl, Franz, 1945-1946 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 71)
    - Morgenstern, Karl, 1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 72)
    - Moser, Carl-Heinz, 1946-1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 73)
    - Mosig, Hans, 1946-1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 74)
    - Müller, Hugo, 1946-1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 75)
    - Noczynski, Georg, 1946-1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 76)
    - Oppenfeld, Horst von, 1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 77)
    - Pfeifer, Ludwig, 1946 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 78)
    - Pohl, Werner, 06/09/1946 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 79)
    - Radinger, Carl, 1946-1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 80)
    - Rätzke, Erich, 1946-1947[?] (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 81)
    - Richter, Hans Werner, 1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 82)
    - Riedel, Bruno, 1946 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 83)
    - Rinderspacher, Fritz, 1946-1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 84)
    - Rugenstein, Kurt, 1947-1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 85)
    - Schermbach, Joachim, 1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 86)
    - Schlesinger, Klaus, 1946 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 87)
    - Schmeller, Theodor [Cron, Lore], 1946 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 88)
    - Schmid, Otto, 1947-1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 89)
    - Schott, Eugen, 1946-1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 90)
    - Schreiber, Eugen, 1946-1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 91)
    - Schwotzer, Helmut, 1946-1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 92)
    - Springe, Freimut, 1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 93)
    - Stillich, Stefan, 1946-1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 94)
    - Trost, Oskar, 1946-1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 95)
    - Tulatz, Herbert A., 1947-1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 96)
    - Ulbrich, Eberhard, 1947-1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 97)
    - Vinz Kurt, 1946-1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 98)
    - Viol, Karl-Heinz, 1946 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 99)
    - Vonderbank, Klaus, 1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 100)
    - Weber, Otto, 1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 101)
    - Weiss, Friedrich K., 1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 102)
    - Welke, Erwin, 1945 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 103)
    - Wiblishauser, Albert, 1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 104)
    - Wieschendorf, August, 1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 105)
    - Wilke, Gerhard, 1946 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 106)
    - Wissmann, Hans, 1946-1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 107)
    - Wittbrodt, Willy, 04/24/1946 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 108)
    - Zander, Wolf Dieter, 1946-1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 109)
    - Zeller, Hermann, 1946-1947 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 110)
    - Miscellaneous correspondents -- former POWs, 1947-1948 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 111)
    - Miscellaneous materials sent to Ehrmann by former POWs, 1948; Undated (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 112)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence related to the Program of Reeducation for German POWs (in English), 1946-1949 (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 113)
- Materials Related to the Reeducation Program for German Prisoners-of-War, 1945-1947; 1982; 3; 6 file folders
  The series contains a typescript entitled "Historical Monograph: Re-education of Enemy Prisoners of War" (2 file folders), which is a large collection of reports, memoranda, copies of letters, and sample examination and questionnaire forms used in the project. Included in the monograph are also: an outline of the series of Ehrmann's lectures "Deutsche Geschichte in neuen Licht", sample issues of POW magazines "Der Ruf" (an English translation) and "Auslese" (in German), and an appendix on the reeducation program of Japanese prisoners-of-war (a short two-page section on Italian POWs appears earlier in the collection). Beyond the monograph, there are several other documents pertaining to the reeducation program, including a report entitled "A Reorientation Program Seen Through the Eyes of German Prisoners" and Ehrmann's report on the German History Department at Forts Getty and Wetherill. The series also contains some educational materials developed especially for the project, such as "Kleiner Führer dürch Amerika", "America from the Inside", and Ehrmann's lectures on the history of Germany, as well as newspaper clippings related to the topic.
  Arranged by subject.
  - "Re-education of Enemy Prisoners of War". Historical monograph, appendices, 1945-1946 (Box 4 (3-Materials Related to the Reeducation Program for G), Folder 114)
  - "Re-education of Enemy Prisoners of War". Folder 2: Supplement, Project II and III, Japanese Program, Eustis Project, Undated (Box 4 (3-Materials Related to the Reeducation Program for G), Folder 115)
  - "I. The Prisoner of War". / "II. The Re-educators", Undated (Box 4 (3-Materials Related to the Reeducation Program for G), Folder 116)
  - Other documents connected with the Reeducation Program, Undated (Box 4 (3-Materials Related to the Reeducation Program for G), Folder 117)
  - Educational materials used in the Reeducation Program, 1945 (Box 4 (3-Materials Related to the Reeducation Program for G), Folder 118)
  - Newspaper articles on the Reeducation Program, 1945-1947; 1982 (Box 4 (3-Materials Related to the Reeducation Program for G), Folder 119)
- Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann, 1931-1989; 4; 85 file folders
  The series contains those Ehrmann's works that were created without reference to his teaching activities: conference and seminar papers, transcripts of radio programs broadcast over the University of Colorado radio network and RIAS Berlin, a draft version of the article "The Practical Application of Political Analysis to the Assessment of Political Risk in Western Europe", newspaper clippings of his articles and letters to editors, as well as 2 sets of reports - "Frankreich Berichte" (for the Institute of Social Research, New York, 1936-1939), describing the political and social situation in France in the 1930s, and reports of the Bureau of Latin American Research, Washington, D.C., focusing on German-language groups in Latin America (1943).
  - Typescripts, primarily speeches, 4.1
    - "Frankreich Berichte" [incomplete], 1936-1939 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 1)
    - First U.S. lecture, 1940-1941 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 2)
    - Reports of the Bureau of Latin American Research, Washington, D.C., 1943 April-1943 July (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 3)
    - "The United Nations and the Czechoslovakian Coup", 1948 April 10 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 4)
    - "Italy after the Elections", 1948 May 1 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 5)
    - "Can Democracy Survive in France?", 1948 October 2 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 6)
    - "The Atlantic Pact", 1949 May 11 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 7)
    - "American Security and Western Europe", 1952 February (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 8)
    - "Pressure Groups in France and the United States", 1955 June (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 9)
    - "Interest Groups and Political Development. An Overview", 1960 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 10)
    - "Außerparlamentarische Machtgruppen in der modernen Demokratie", 1964 November 30 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 11)
    - "Memories of Arnold Brecht: A Political Practitioner and Theorist", Fall 1977 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 12)
    - "Die Grenzen der Justiz im Wohlfahrtsstaat -- eine amerikanische Debatte" (Mannheim, 1982 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 13)
    - "The Judicial Elites of Germany from Empire to Bonn", 1985 July (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 14)
    - "Constraints on Parliament: The Constitutional Council", ca. 1987 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 15)
    - "Berlin Festvortrag", 1989 April (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 16)
    - "The Practical Application of Political Analysis to the Assessment of Political Risk in Western Europe", Undated (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 17)
    - "Political Oppositions in Western Europe -- Dahl et.al. revisited", Undated (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 18)
  - Publications, 4.2
    - "Konkurrenz eines allgemeinverbindlichen mit einem gewöhnlichen Tarifvertrage", 1931 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 19)
    - "Auslegungsstreitigkeiten über den Inhalt eines mehrgliedrigen Tarifvertrags", 1932 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 20)
    - "Recht auf Abwehrkampf bei Verletzung eines mehrgliedrigen Tarifvertrages", 1932 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 21)
    - Der mehrgliedrige Tarifvertrag, 1932 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 22)
    - "Kampf einer Republik", 1934 November (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 23)
    - Alsen, Fritz. "Faschismus an der macht", 1935 May-1935 June (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 24)
    - Alsen, Fritz. "Die Jakobiner Legende", 1936 February (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 25)
    - Alsen, Fritz. "Napoleon III. und Hitler", 1936 April (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 26)
    - Alsen, Fritz. "Die Volksfront in Frankreich", 1936 July-1936 August (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 27)
    - Bernard, Paul. "Le mouvement ouvrier en France pendant les années 1852-1864 d'après les rapports politiques des procureurs généraux. Documents inédits", 1938 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 28)
    - "Labor's Rights", 1941 August (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 29)
    - "The Blum Experiment and the Fall of France", 1941 October (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 30)
    - "Washington's Plan for Germany", 1943 May 3 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 31)
    - "The Duty of Disclosure in Parliamentary Investigation: A Comparative Study", 1943 December (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 32)
    - "The Trade Union Movement in the Framework of French War Economy, 1939-1940", 1944 August (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 33)
    - Kleiner Führer durch Amerika, 1945 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 34)
    - "France Builds Her Future", 1945 December 10 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 35)
    - "An Experiment in Political Education: The Prisoner-of-War Schools in the United States", 1947 September (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 36)
    - "Information on Today's World Needed By All Campus Community", [1948] (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 37)
    - "Deutsche Geschichte im neuen Licht", 1948 June (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 38)
    - "Political Forces in Present-Day France", 1948 June (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 39)
    - Gulick, Charles A.Austria from Habsburg to Hitler (review), 1948 September (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 40)
    - "France and the United Nations", 1948 October 17 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 41)
    - "Our Tragic Choice in China", 1948 November 12 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 42)
    - "France Between East and West", 1949 March (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 43)
    - "A Communist Party in America", Summer 1949 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 44)
    - "The Real Facts About the 'Fact' Sheet", 1950 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 45)
    - "French Views on Communism", 1950 October (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 46)
    - "The Decline of the Socialist Party", 1951 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 47)
    - "The Zeitgeist and the Supreme Court", 1951 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 48)
    - Mario Einaudi, Jean-Marie Domenach, Aldo Garosci.Communism in Western Europe (review, 1951 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 49)